[
    {
        "question": "1. What is data visualization in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Data visualization is a way to represent data that is visually appealing and interactive. With advancements in technology, the number of business intelligence tools has increased which helps users understand data, data sets, data points, charts, graphs, and focus on its impact rather than understanding the tool itself. visually appealing and interactive",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the advantages of Tableau?",
        "answer": "Some of the advantages of using Tableau: Data visualization: Rather than having complex computations over an Excel sheet, Tableau provides beautiful insights, data blending, and dashboarding derived from the data.\nCreate interactive visualizations: Tableau provides a drag-n-drop facility to quickly let the users interact with the data. You can check some of the templates created using Tableau in the Tableau gallery. \nWith Tableau’s gallery of templates, you can choose your option and customize it. With data visualization features, you can easily embed tons of information in the form of infographics that appeal to the audience.\nEase of implementation: With drag-and-drop options, Tableau is reportedly easier to use. This is one such tool that you can learn without having any coding background or experience in Python, Business objects, or DOMO.\nHandle large amounts of data: Tableau is competent enough to handle millions of rows without affecting the dashboard performance.\nIntegration of scripting languages: With Tableau, you can perform complex data computations using scripting languages like Python and R by importing some visuals or packages.\nWith much hype around data analytics and visualization, it is important to get well-versed with the tools simplifying the data journey. We have curated a list of interview questions ranging from beginner’s level to expert to help you land a job in your preferred expertise. Data visualization: Rather than having complex computations over an Excel sheet, Tableau provides beautiful insights, data blending, and dashboarding derived from the data. Data visualization: Create interactive visualizations: Tableau provides a drag-n-drop facility to quickly let the users interact with the data. You can check some of the templates created using Tableau in the Tableau gallery. \nWith Tableau’s gallery of templates, you can choose your option and customize it. With data visualization features, you can easily embed tons of information in the form of infographics that appeal to the audience. Create interactive visualizations:  Ease of implementation: With drag-and-drop options, Tableau is reportedly easier to use. This is one such tool that you can learn without having any coding background or experience in Python, Business objects, or DOMO. Ease of implementation: Handle large amounts of data: Tableau is competent enough to handle millions of rows without affecting the dashboard performance. Handle large amounts of data: Integration of scripting languages: With Tableau, you can perform complex data computations using scripting languages like Python and R by importing some visuals or packages. Integration of scripting languages: With much hype around data analytics and visualization, it is important to get well-versed with the tools simplifying the data journey. We have curated a list of interview questions ranging from beginner’s level to expert to help you land a job in your preferred expertise. With much hype around data analytics and visualization",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the difference between various BI tools and Tableau?",
        "answer": "The basic difference between the traditional BI tools and Tableau lies in the efficiency and speed. The architecture of Traditional BI tools has hardware limitations. While Tableau does not have any sort of dependencies\nThe traditional BI tools work on complex technologies while Tableau uses simple associative search to make it dynamic. \nTraditional BI tools do not support multi-thread, in-memory, or multi-core computing while Tableau supports all these features after integrating complex technologies. \nTraditional BI tools have a pre-defined data view while Tableau does a predictive analysis for business operations. The architecture of Traditional BI tools has hardware limitations. While Tableau does not have any sort of dependencies The traditional BI tools work on complex technologies while Tableau uses simple associative search to make it dynamic. Traditional BI tools do not support multi-thread, in-memory, or multi-core computing while Tableau supports all these features after integrating complex technologies. Traditional BI tools have a pre-defined data view while Tableau does a predictive analysis for business operations.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are different Tableau products?",
        "answer": "Tableau like other BI tools has a range of products: Tableau Desktop: Desktop product is used to create optimized queries out from pictures of data. Once the queries are ready, you can perform those queries without the need to code. Tableau desktop encompasses data from various sources into its data engine and creates an interactive dashboard. \nTableau Server: When you have published dashboards using Tableau Desktop, Tableau servers help in sharing them throughout the organization. It is an enterprise-level feature that is installed on a Windows or Linux server. \nTableau Reader: Tableau Reader is a free feature available on Desktop that lets you open and views data visualizations. You can filter or drill down the data but restricts editing any formulas or performing any kind of actions on it. It is also used to extract connection files. \nTableau Online: Tableau online is also a paid feature but doesn’t need exclusive installation. It comes with the software and is used to share the published dashboards anywhere and everywhere. \nTableau Public: Tableau public is yet another free feature to view your data visualizations by saving them as worksheets or workbooks on Tableau Server. Tableau Desktop: Desktop product is used to create optimized queries out from pictures of data. Once the queries are ready, you can perform those queries without the need to code. Tableau desktop encompasses data from various sources into its data engine and creates an interactive dashboard. Tableau Desktop: Tableau Server: When you have published dashboards using Tableau Desktop, Tableau servers help in sharing them throughout the organization. It is an enterprise-level feature that is installed on a Windows or Linux server. Tableau Server: Tableau Reader: Tableau Reader is a free feature available on Desktop that lets you open and views data visualizations. You can filter or drill down the data but restricts editing any formulas or performing any kind of actions on it. It is also used to extract connection files. Tableau Reader: Tableau Online: Tableau online is also a paid feature but doesn’t need exclusive installation. It comes with the software and is used to share the published dashboards anywhere and everywhere. Tableau Online: Tableau Public: Tableau public is yet another free feature to view your data visualizations by saving them as worksheets or workbooks on Tableau Server. Tableau Public:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is a parameter in Tableau?",
        "answer": "The parameter is a variable (numbers, strings, or date) created to replace a constant value in calculations, filters, or reference lines. For example, you create a field that returns true if the sales are greater than 30,000 and false if otherwise. Parameters are used to replace these numbers (30000 in this case) to dynamically set this during calculations. Parameters allow you to dynamically modify values in a calculation. The parameters can accept values in the following options: variable (numbers, strings, or date) All: Simple text field\nList: List of possible values to select from\nRange: Select values from a specified range All: Simple text field All: List: List of possible values to select from List: Range: Select values from a specified range Range:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Tell me something about measures and dimensions?",
        "answer": "In Tableau, when we connect to a new data source, each field in the data source is either mapped as measures or dimensions. These fields are the columns defined in the data source. Each field is assigned a dataType (integer, string, etc.) and a role (discrete dimension or continuous measure). connect to a new data source measures dimensions Measures contain numeric values that are analyzed by a dimension table. Measures are stored in a table that allows storage of multiple records and contains foreign keys referring uniquely to the associated dimension tables. While Dimensions contain qualitative values (name, dates, geographical data) to define comprehensive attributes to categorize, segment, and reveal the data details.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are continuous and discrete field types?",
        "answer": "Tableau’s specialty lies in displaying data differently either in continuous format or discrete. Both of them are mathematical terms used to define data where continuous means without interruptions and discrete means are individually separate and distinct. While the blue color indicates discrete behavior, the green color indicates continuous behavior. On one hand, the discrete view defines the headers and can be easily sorted, while continuous defines the axis in a graph view and cannot be sorted. Discrete View Tableau  Discrete View Tableau Image - tableau.com",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is aggregation and disaggregation of data?",
        "answer": "Aggregation of data means displaying the measures and dimensions in an aggregated form. The aggregate functions available in the Tableau tool are: SUM (expression): Adds up all the values used in the expression. Used only for numeric values.\nAVG (expression): Calculates the average of all the values used in the expression. Used only for numeric values.\nMedian (expression): Calculates the median of all the values across all the records used in the expression. Used only for numeric values.\nCount (expression): Returns the number of values in the set of expressions. Excludes null values.\nCount (distinct): Returns the number of unique values in the set of expressions. SUM (expression): Adds up all the values used in the expression. Used only for numeric values. SUM (expression): AVG (expression): Calculates the average of all the values used in the expression. Used only for numeric values. AVG (expression): Median (expression): Calculates the median of all the values across all the records used in the expression. Used only for numeric values. Median (expression): Count (expression): Returns the number of values in the set of expressions. Excludes null values. Count (expression): Count (distinct): Returns the number of unique values in the set of expressions. Count (distinct): Tableau, in fact, lets you alter the aggregation type for a view. Disaggregation of data means displaying each and every data field separately.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the different types of joins in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Tableau is pretty similar to SQL. Therefore, the types of joins in Tableau are similar: Left Outer Join: Extracts all the records from the left table and the matching rows from the right table.\nRight Outer Join: Extracts all the records from the right table and the matching rows from the left table.\nFull Outer Join: Extracts the records from both the left and right tables. All unmatched rows go with the NULL value. \nInner Join: Extracts the records from both tables. Left Outer Join: Extracts all the records from the left table and the matching rows from the right table. Left Outer Join: Right Outer Join: Extracts all the records from the right table and the matching rows from the left table. Right Outer Join: Full Outer Join: Extracts the records from both the left and right tables. All unmatched rows go with the NULL value. Full Outer Join: Inner Join: Extracts the records from both tables. Inner Join: Learn More Learn More Joins in Tableau  Joins in Tableau",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Tell me the different connections to make with a dataset?",
        "answer": "There are two types of data connections in Tableau: LIVE: Live connection is a dynamic way to extract real-time data by directly connecting to the data source. Tableau directly creates queries against the database entries and retrieves the query results in a workbook. LIVE: EXTRACT: A snapshot of the data, extract the file (.tde or .hyper file) contains data from a relational database. The data is extracted from a static source of data like an Excel Spreadsheet. You can schedule to refresh the snapshots which are done using the Tableau server. This doesn’t need any connection with the database. EXTRACT:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are the supported file extensions in Tableau?",
        "answer": "The supported file extensions used in Tableau Desktop are: Tableau Workbook (TWB): contains all worksheets, story points, dashboards, etc.\nTableau Data Source (TDS): contains connection information and metadata about your data source\nTableau Data Extract (TDE): contains data that has been extracted from other data sources.\nTableau Packaged Workbook (TWBX): contains a combination of the workbook, connection data, and metadata, and the data itself in the form of TDE.  It can be zipped and shared.\nTableau Packaged Data Source (TDSX): contains a combination of different files.\nTableau Bookmark (TBM): to earmark a specific worksheet. Tableau Workbook (TWB): contains all worksheets, story points, dashboards, etc. Tableau Workbook (TWB) Tableau Data Source (TDS): contains connection information and metadata about your data source Tableau Data Source (TDS): Tableau Data Extract (TDE): contains data that has been extracted from other data sources. Tableau Data Extract (TDE): Tableau Packaged Workbook (TWBX): contains a combination of the workbook, connection data, and metadata, and the data itself in the form of TDE.  It can be zipped and shared. Tableau Packaged Workbook (TWBX): Tableau Packaged Data Source (TDSX): contains a combination of different files. Tableau Packaged Data Source (TDSX): Tableau Bookmark (TBM): to earmark a specific worksheet. Tableau Bookmark (TBM):",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are the supported data types in Tableau?",
        "answer": "The following data types are supported in Tableau: DataType Possible Values\nBoolean True/False\nDate Date Value (December 28, 2016)\nDate & Time Date & Timestamp values (December 28, 2016 \n06:00:00 PM)\nGeographical Values Geographical Mapping (Beijing, Mumbai)\nText/String Text/String\nNumber Decimal (8.00)\nNumber Whole Number (5) DataType Possible Values\nBoolean True/False\nDate Date Value (December 28, 2016)\nDate & Time Date & Timestamp values (December 28, 2016 \n06:00:00 PM)\nGeographical Values Geographical Mapping (Beijing, Mumbai)\nText/String Text/String\nNumber Decimal (8.00)\nNumber Whole Number (5) DataType Possible Values DataType Possible Values DataType Possible Values Boolean True/False\nDate Date Value (December 28, 2016)\nDate & Time Date & Timestamp values (December 28, 2016 \n06:00:00 PM)\nGeographical Values Geographical Mapping (Beijing, Mumbai)\nText/String Text/String\nNumber Decimal (8.00)\nNumber Whole Number (5) Boolean True/False Boolean True/False Date Date Value (December 28, 2016) Date Date Value (December 28, 2016) Date & Time Date & Timestamp values (December 28, 2016 \n06:00:00 PM) Date & Time Date & Timestamp values (December 28, 2016 \n06:00:00 PM)  Geographical Values Geographical Mapping (Beijing, Mumbai) Geographical Values Geographical Mapping (Beijing, Mumbai) Text/String Text/String Text/String Text/String Number Decimal (8.00) Number Decimal (8.00) Number Whole Number (5) Number Whole Number (5)",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are sets?",
        "answer": "Sets are custom fields created as a subset of the data in your Tableau desktop. Sets can be computed based on conditions or created manually based on the dimensions of the data source. \nFor example, A set of customers that earned revenue more than some value. Now, set data may update dynamically based on the conditions applied. Learn More  Learn More",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are groups in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Groups are created to visualize larger memberships using dimensions. Groups can create their own fields to categorize values in that specific dimension.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What are shelves?",
        "answer": "Tableau worksheets contain various named elements like columns, rows, marks, filters, pages, etc. which are called shelves. You can place fields on shelves to create visualizations, increase the level of detail, or add context to it.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Tell me something about Data blending in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Data blending is viewing and analyzing data from multiple sources in one place. Primary and secondary are two types of data sources that are involved in data blending.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. How do you generally perform load testing in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Load testing in Tableau is done to understand the server’s capacity with respect to its environment, data, workload, and use. It is preferable to conduct load testing at least 3-4 times in a year because with every new user, upgrade, or content authoring, the usage, data, and workload change. Tabjolt was created by Tableau to conduct point-and-run load and performance testing specifically for Tableau servers. Tabjolt: Automates the process of user-specified loads\nEliminates dependency on script development or script maintenance\nScales linearly with an increase in the load by adding more nodes to the cluster Automates the process of user-specified loads Eliminates dependency on script development or script maintenance Scales linearly with an increase in the load by adding more nodes to the cluster",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Why would someone not use Tableau?",
        "answer": "The limitations of using Tableau are: Not cost-effective: Tableau is not that cost-effective when we compare it well with the other available data visualization tools. In addition to this, it has software upgrades, proper deployment, maintenance, and also training people for using the tool.\nNot so secure: When it comes to data, everyone is extra cautious. Tableau focussed on security issues but fails to provide centralized data-level security. It pushes for row-level security and creates an account for every user which makes it more prone to security glitches.\nBI capabilities are not enough: Tableau lacks basic BI capabilities like large-scale reporting, building data tables, or creating static layouts. It has limited result-sharing capabilities, email notification configuration is limited to admins, and the vendor doesn’t support trigger-based notifications. Not cost-effective: Tableau is not that cost-effective when we compare it well with the other available data visualization tools. In addition to this, it has software upgrades, proper deployment, maintenance, and also training people for using the tool. Not cost-effective: Not so secure: When it comes to data, everyone is extra cautious. Tableau focussed on security issues but fails to provide centralized data-level security. It pushes for row-level security and creates an account for every user which makes it more prone to security glitches. Not so secure: BI capabilities are not enough: Tableau lacks basic BI capabilities like large-scale reporting, building data tables, or creating static layouts. It has limited result-sharing capabilities, email notification configuration is limited to admins, and the vendor doesn’t support trigger-based notifications. BI capabilities are not enough:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are different Tableau files?",
        "answer": "Workbooks: Workbooks contain one or more worksheets and dashboard elements.\nBookmarks: Contains a single worksheet that is easier to share.\nPackaged Workbooks: Contains a workbook along with supporting local file data and background images.\nData Extraction Files: Extract files that contain a subset of data.\nData Connection Files: Small XML file with various connection information. Workbooks: Workbooks contain one or more worksheets and dashboard elements. Workbooks: Bookmarks: Contains a single worksheet that is easier to share. Bookmarks: Packaged Workbooks: Contains a workbook along with supporting local file data and background images. Packaged Workbooks: Data Extraction Files: Extract files that contain a subset of data. Data Extraction Files: Data Connection Files: Small XML file with various connection information. Data Connection Files:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is the story in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Creating a story is effective in Tableau which is created by combining various charts to portray a plot of viewers. A story is a sheet that contains all the methods used to create those worksheets. To create a story: Click the New Story on the dashboard.\nChoose the right size of the story from the bottom-left corner or choose a custom size.\nStart building the story by double-clicking the sheet and add it to the story point.\nAdd a caption to the story by clicking Add a caption.\nYou can update the highlights by clicking Update in the toolbar. You can also add layout options, format a story, or fit the story to your dashboard. Click the New Story on the dashboard. Choose the right size of the story from the bottom-left corner or choose a custom size. Start building the story by double-clicking the sheet and add it to the story point. Add a caption to the story by clicking Add a caption. You can update the highlights by clicking Update in the toolbar. You can also add layout options, format a story, or fit the story to your dashboard.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is a TDE file?",
        "answer": "TDE is Tableau Desktop Extension with extension .tde. TDE file points to a file that contains data from external sources like MS Excel, MS Access, or CSV files. TDE makes it easier to analyze and discover data.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are the components in a dashboard?",
        "answer": "The components displayed in a dashboard are: Horizontal: Horizontal view allows the users to combine the worksheets and dashboard elements from left to right and edit the height of the elements.\nVertical: Vertical view allows the users to combine the worksheets and dashboard elements from top to bottom and edit the width of the elements.\nText: All the textual fields.\nImage Extract: To extract an image Tableau applies some code, extracts the image, and saves it in a workbook in the XML format.\nWeb URL: Hyperlink that points to a web page, file, or other web resources outside of Tableau Horizontal: Horizontal view allows the users to combine the worksheets and dashboard elements from left to right and edit the height of the elements. Horizontal: Vertical: Vertical view allows the users to combine the worksheets and dashboard elements from top to bottom and edit the width of the elements. Vertical: Text: All the textual fields. Text: Image Extract: To extract an image Tableau applies some code, extracts the image, and saves it in a workbook in the XML format. Image Extract: Web URL: Hyperlink that points to a web page, file, or other web resources outside of Tableau Web URL:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are extracts and schedules in Tableau server?",
        "answer": "Data extracts are the subsets of data created from data sources. Schedules are scheduled refreshes made on extracts after publishing the workbook. This keeps the data up-to-date. Schedules are strictly managed by the server administrators.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is the difference between a tree and heat map?",
        "answer": "Both the maps help in analyzing data. While a heat map visualizes and compares different categories of data, a treemap displays a hierarchical structure of data in rectangles. Heat map visualizes measures against dimensions by depicting them in different colors. Similar to a text table with values defined in different colors. Heatmap In Tableau  Heatmap In Tableau Treemap visualizes the hierarchy of data in nested rectangles. Hierarchy levels are displayed from larger rectangles to smaller ones. Example - Below treemap shows aggregated sales totals across a range of product categories: TreeMap in Tableau  TreeMap in Tableau Image - tableau.com tableau.com",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are dual axes?",
        "answer": "Dual axes are used to analyze two different measures at two different scales in the same graph. This lets you compare multiple attributes on one graph with two independent axes layered one above the other. To add a measure as a dual-axis, drag the field to the right side of the view and drop it when you see a black dashed line appear. You can also right-click (control-click on Mac) the measure on the Columns or Rows shelf and select Dual Axis.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are the various types of filters in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Tableau has 6 different types of filters: Extract Filter: This filter retrieves a subset of data from the data source.\nDimension Filter: This filter is for non-aggregated data (discrete).\nData Source Filter: This filter refrains users from viewing sensitive information and thus reduces data feeds.\nContext Filter: This filter creates datasets by applying presets in Tableau.\nMeasure Filter: This filter applies various operations like sum, median, avg, etc.\nTable Calculation Filter: This filter is applied after the view has been created. Extract Filter: This filter retrieves a subset of data from the data source. Extract Filter: Dimension Filter: This filter is for non-aggregated data (discrete). Dimension Filter: Data Source Filter: This filter refrains users from viewing sensitive information and thus reduces data feeds. Data Source Filter: Context Filter: This filter creates datasets by applying presets in Tableau. Context Filter: Measure Filter: This filter applies various operations like sum, median, avg, etc. Measure Filter: Table Calculation Filter: This filter is applied after the view has been created. Table Calculation Filter:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is Tableau data engine?",
        "answer": "An analytical database that computes instant query responses, predictive analysis of the server, and integrated data. The data engine is useful when you need to create, refresh, or query extracts. It can be used for cross-database joins as well.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. How do you embed views into webpages?",
        "answer": "You can easily integrate interactive views from your Tableau Server or Tableau online onto webpages, blogs, web applications, or internet portals. But to have a look at the views, the permissions demand the viewer to create an account on the Tableau Server. To embed views, click the Share button on the top of the view and copy the embed code to paste it on the web page. You can also customize the embedded code or Tableau Javascript APIs to embed views.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is the maximum no. of rows Tableau can utilize at one time?",
        "answer": "The maximum number of rows or columns is indefinite because even though Tableau contains petabytes of data, it intelligently uses only those rows and columns which you need to extract for your purpose.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Mention what is the difference between published data sources and embedded data sources in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Connection information is the details of data that you want to bring into Tableau. Before publishing it, you can create an extract of the same. Published Data Source: It contains connection information that is independent of any workbook. Embedded Data Source: It contains connection information which is connected to a workbook",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is the DRIVE Program Methodology?",
        "answer": "DRIVE program methodology creates a structure around data analytics derived from enterprise deployments. The drive methodology is iterative in nature and includes agile methods that are faster and effective.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. How to use groups in a calculated field?",
        "answer": "Add the ‘GroupBy’ clause to SQL queries or create a calculated field in the data window to group fields. Using groups in a calculation. You cannot reference ad-hoc groups in a calculation.\nBlend data using groups created in the secondary data source: Only calculated groups can be used in data blending if the group was created in the secondary data source.\nUse a group in another workbook. You can easily replicate a group in another workbook by copy and pasting a calculation. Using groups in a calculation. You cannot reference ad-hoc groups in a calculation. Blend data using groups created in the secondary data source: Only calculated groups can be used in data blending if the group was created in the secondary data source. Use a group in another workbook. You can easily replicate a group in another workbook by copy and pasting a calculation.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Explain when would you use Joins vs. Blending in Tableau?",
        "answer": "While the two terms may sound similar, there is a difference in their meaning and use in Tableau: While Join is used to combine two or more tables within the same data source. Blending is used to combine data from multiple data sources such as Oracle, Excel, SQL server, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is Assume referential integrity?",
        "answer": "In some cases, you can improve query performance by selecting the option to Assume Referential Integrity from the Data menu. When you use this option, Tableau will include the joined table in the query only if it is specifically referenced by fields in the view.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is a Calculated Field, and How Will You Create One?",
        "answer": "Calculated fields are created using formulas based on other fields. These fields do not exist but are created by you. You can create these fields to: You can create these fields to: Segment data\nConvert the data type of a field, such as converting a string to a date.\nAggregate data\nFilter results\nCalculate ratios Segment data Convert the data type of a field, such as converting a string to a date. Aggregate data Filter results Calculate ratios There are three main types of calculations that you can create: Basic Calculations: Transform values of the data fields at the source level\nLevel of Detail (LOD) Expressions: Transform values of the data fields at the source level like basic calculations but with more granular access\nTable Calculations: Transform values of the data fields only at the visualization level Basic Calculations: Transform values of the data fields at the source level Level of Detail (LOD) Expressions: Transform values of the data fields at the source level like basic calculations but with more granular access Table Calculations: Transform values of the data fields only at the visualization level To create calculate fields: To create calculate fields: In Tableau, navigate to Analysis>Create a calculated field. Input details in the calculation editor.\nAnd, done! ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is the Rank Function in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Rank function is used to give positions (rank) to any measure in the data set. Tableau can rank measure in the following ways: Rank: The rank function in Tableau accepts two arguments: aggregated measure and ranking order (optional) with a default value of desc.\nRank_dense: The rank_dense also accepts the two arguments: aggregated measure and ranking order. This assigns the same rank to the same values but doesn’t stop there and keeps incrementing with the other values. For instance, if you have values 10, 20, 20, 30, then ranks will be 1, 2, 2, 3.\nRank_modified: The rank_modified assigns the same rank to similar values.\nRank_unique: The rank_unique assigns a unique rank to each and every value. For example, If the values are 10, 20, 20, 30 then the assigned ranks will be 1,2,3,4 respectively. Rank: The rank function in Tableau accepts two arguments: aggregated measure and ranking order (optional) with a default value of desc. Rank_dense: The rank_dense also accepts the two arguments: aggregated measure and ranking order. This assigns the same rank to the same values but doesn’t stop there and keeps incrementing with the other values. For instance, if you have values 10, 20, 20, 30, then ranks will be 1, 2, 2, 3. Rank_modified: The rank_modified assigns the same rank to similar values. Rank_unique: The rank_unique assigns a unique rank to each and every value. For example, If the values are 10, 20, 20, 30 then the assigned ranks will be 1,2,3,4 respectively.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. How Can You Display the Top Five and Bottom Five Sales in the Same View?",
        "answer": "You can see top five and bottom five sales with the help of these functions: Drag ‘customer name’ to row and sales to the column.\nSort Sum(sales) in descending order.\nCreate a calculated field ‘Rank of Sales’. Drag ‘customer name’ to row and sales to the column. Sort Sum(sales) in descending order. Create a calculated field ‘Rank of Sales’.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is the difference between Tableau and other similar tools like QlikView or IBM Cognos?",
        "answer": "Tableau is different than QlikView or IBM Cognos for various reasons: Tableau is an intuitive data visualization tool simplifying the story creation by simple drag and drop techniques. On the other hand, BI tools like QlikView or Cognos convert data into metadata to let the users explore data relations. If your presentation runs around presenting data in aesthetic visualizations then opt for Tableau. If not, and might need a full BI platform then go for Cognos/QlikView\nThe ease of use or extracting data details is easier in Tableau than compared to extensive BI tools like Cognos. With Tableau, your team members, be it a guy from sales can easily read the data and give insights. But with Cognos, only members with extensive tool knowledge are appreciated and welcomed. Tableau is an intuitive data visualization tool simplifying the story creation by simple drag and drop techniques. On the other hand, BI tools like QlikView or Cognos convert data into metadata to let the users explore data relations. If your presentation runs around presenting data in aesthetic visualizations then opt for Tableau. If not, and might need a full BI platform then go for Cognos/QlikView The ease of use or extracting data details is easier in Tableau than compared to extensive BI tools like Cognos. With Tableau, your team members, be it a guy from sales can easily read the data and give insights. But with Cognos, only members with extensive tool knowledge are appreciated and welcomed. Tips to clear an interview To clear interview for Tableau, follow these tips: Focus on the fundamentals: What is Tableau and its working. How calculations work or how a query is processed when visualization is created.\nThoroughly know about Dimensions and Measures because that is one of the important concepts in Tableau.\nGet acquainted with the best practices of creating dashboards and visualizations and also discrete and continuous views.\nExplain why you like Tableau or how it differs from other similar tools like QlikView or IBM Cognos. Your interest in BI tools will put you ahead in the competition.\nWhat are the scenarios where you’ll use Live connection or Data extract in Tableau?\nHow dashboards are deployed on the Server.\nWhat was the maximum amount of data you have handled in Tableau? If you are learning Tableau, while practicing, check the size of your visualization or the TDE file.\nCreate some visualization stories for sample work.\nHow you will take requirements before creating a dashboarding application.\nWhat was your development methodology: Waterfall or Agile?\nHow much time it takes you to create a dashboard. Focus on the fundamentals: What is Tableau and its working. How calculations work or how a query is processed when visualization is created. Thoroughly know about Dimensions and Measures because that is one of the important concepts in Tableau. Get acquainted with the best practices of creating dashboards and visualizations and also discrete and continuous views. Explain why you like Tableau or how it differs from other similar tools like QlikView or IBM Cognos. Your interest in BI tools will put you ahead in the competition. What are the scenarios where you’ll use Live connection or Data extract in Tableau? How dashboards are deployed on the Server. What was the maximum amount of data you have handled in Tableau? If you are learning Tableau, while practicing, check the size of your visualization or the TDE file. Create some visualization stories for sample work. How you will take requirements before creating a dashboarding application. What was your development methodology: Waterfall or Agile? How much time it takes you to create a dashboard.  Important Resource Important Resource Tableau vs Power BI Tableau vs Power BI Free Data Science online course Free Data Science online course",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is Tableau?",
        "answer": "ADVERTISEMENT\nableau is a powerful data visualization tool used in the business intelligence industry.\nIt simplifies the raw data into a very easily understandable format.\nIt visualizes and creates interactive, sharable dashboards.\nTableau is not required any technical or programming skills.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) Explain the features of Tableau?",
        "answer": "There are three main features of Tableau, such as:\nData Blending: Data blending is an essential feature in Tableau. It is used when we combine related data from multiple data sources, which you want to analyze together in a single view, and represent in the form of a graph.\nReal-time Analysis: Real-Time Analysis makes users able to quickly understand and analyze dynamic data when the Velocity is high, and real-time analysis of data is complicated. Tableau can help extract valuable information from fast-moving data with interactive analytics.\nThe Collaboration of Data: Data analysis is not isolating task. That's why Tableau is built for collaboration. Team members can share data, make follow up queries, and forward easy-to-digest visualizations to others who could gain value from the data. Making sure everyone understands the data and can make informed decisions is critical to success.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) How many tools in Tableau?",
        "answer": "There are five tools in Tableau, such as:\nTableau Desktop: Tableau Desktop establish connectivity between the Data Warehouse and other various types of files. The dashboards and the workbooks created here can be either shared locally or publicly. It allows us to code and customizes reports. Right from establishing the stories, charts to blending them all to form a dashboard, all the necessary work is created in Tableau Desktop.\nTableau Public: This Tableau version is specially built for cost-effective users. The word 'Public' means that the created workbooks cannot be saved locally. They should be kept on the Tableau's public cloud, which can be accessed and viewed by anyone.\nTableau Online: Its functionality is similar to the Tableau server, but data is stored on the server that hosted on the cloud, which is maintained by the Tableau group. There is no storage limit on the data which is published in the Tableau Online. Tableau Online creates a direct link over 40 data sources who are hosted in the cloud such as the Hive, MySQL, Spark SQL, Amazon Aurora, and many more.\nTableau Server: The software is correctly used to share the workbooks, visualizations, which is created in the Tableau Desktop application over the organization. To share dashboards in the Tableau Server, you should first publish your workbook in the Tableau Desktop. Once the workbook has been uploaded to the server, it will be accessible only to the authorized users.\nTableau Reader: Tableau Reader is a free tool which allows us to view the visualizations and workbooks, which is created using Tableau Desktop or Tableau Public. The data can be filtered, but modifications and editing are restricted. There is no security in Tableau Reader as anyone can view workbook using Tableau Reader.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) Explain all data terminologies in Tableau?",
        "answer": "There are several types of data terminologies in Tableau, such as:\nBookmark: A .tbm document in the bookmarks folder in the Tableau repository that contains a single worksheet. It helps in improving data analysis. Unlike, web browser bookmarks, .tbm files are a compatible way to display various studies quickly.\nWorkbook: A workbook is a file with .twb extension that holds one or more worksheets as well as dashboards and stories.\nDashboard: The dashboard is a combination of several views that are arranged on a single page. In Tableau, dashboards are used to observe and compare a variety of data together, and also it allows interacting with other worksheets.\nData Source Page: Data Source is a page where you can set up your data source. Does this data source page generally consist of four main areas? Join area, left pane, a preview area, and metadata area.\nWorksheet: The worksheet is a collection of sheets. It's a place where you build views of your data by dragging various fields onto the shelves.\nDimensions: Dimension is commonly known as a field of categorical data. Dimensions hold discrete data such as members and hierarchies that cannot be aggregated. It also contains characteristic values such as dates, names, and geographical data. The dimensions used to reveal details of your information.\nMeasures: measures are the measurable quantities of the data, which can be analyzed by a dimension table. Measures are stored in a table which contains foreign keys referring uniquely to the associated dimension tables. The table supports data storage at the atomic level and thus, allows the number of records to be inserted at one time.\nFor example, a Sales table can have a product key, customer key, promotion key, items sold, referring to a specific event.\nFilters shelf: Filter shelf is located on the left side of the workbook. Filters shelf is used to exclude the data from a view by filtering it using both dimensions and measures.\nPages shelf: Page shelf is on the left side of the view. With the help of the page shelf, you can split a view into a sequence of pages based on the values and members in a continuous or discrete field. Adding a field with the pages shelf is similar to adding a field in rows shelf. For each new row, a new page is created.\nMarks card: Marks card is on the left side of the worksheet. The user can drag fields to the control mark properties such as color, type, shape, size, label, detail, and tooltip.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "twbx extension?",
        "answer": ".twb .twbx\nA .twb is an xml document that contains the information about your dashboards, sheets, and stories. It doesn't contain any data so to share your workbook, and you have send both workbook file and the data source file of Tableau.\nA .twbx is a package of files \"compressed\" together. It includes data source file and any other file used to produce the workbook, including images.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What is the difference between traditional BI tools and Tableau?",
        "answer": "Traditional BI tools Tableau\nTraditional BI architecture has hardware limitations. Tableau doesn't have dependencies.\nIt based on the complex set of technologies. Tableau based associative search that makes it fast and dynamic.\nIt does not support in-memory, multi-thread, and multi-core computing. It supports in-memory when used with advanced technologies.\nIt has a predefined view of data. It uses predictive analysis for various business operations.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are the different data types in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Tableau expresses fields and assigns data types automatically. If the data source appoints the data type, Tableau will use that data type. If the data source doesn't individually assign a data type, Tableau will assign one. Tableau consist of the following data types:\nDate values\nText values\nNumerical values\nDate and time values\nBoolean values (True or False conditions)\nGeographic values (longitude and latitude used for maps)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What are the different types of joins in Tableau?",
        "answer": "The joins in Tableau are the same as SQL joins. There are five main joins, such as:\n1) Cross Joins: Cross join produces rows which combine each row from the first table with each row from the second table.\n\n2) Inner Joins: An inner join returns the matching rows from the tables that are being merged.\n\n3) Left Outer Join: The left outer join returns matching rows from the tables being joined, and also non-matching rows from the left table in the result and places NULL values in the attributes that come from the right table.\n\n4) Right Outer Join: The right outer join operation returns matching rows from the tables being merged, and also non-matching rows from the right table as the result and places NULL values in the attributes that come from the left table.\n\n\n4) Full Outer Join: The full outer join is used to combine tables. As a result, it contains all values from both tables.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) How many tables you can join in Tableau?",
        "answer": "In Tableau, you can join an atmost 32 tables.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) Explain the different connections you can make with your datasets?",
        "answer": "We can connect the datasets in two ways, such as:\n\nLive: Live connection sends queries to your database and retrieves data. These queries will return whatever data is currently in the database.\nExtract: Extracts connection saved subsets of data that use to improve performance or to take the advantages of Tableau functionality which are not supported or available in your original data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What are Shelves?",
        "answer": "Shelves are the named areas placed on the left and top of the view in the worksheet. You can build a view by drag and drop fields onto the shelves. Some shelves are available when you select a specific mark type.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the Sets?",
        "answer": "In Tableau, sets are used to create subsets of data based on the specific condition defined by the user. Sets are only created based on the dimension field.\nThere are two types of sets in Tableau, such as:\nDynamic Sets: The values or members in the dynamic sets get change when the underlying data changes.\nFixed Sets: The values or members in the fixed sets does not change when the underlying data changes.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What are Groups?",
        "answer": "A group is a combination of the members of the dimension which make higher-level categories.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is the Hierarchical Field?",
        "answer": "In Tableau a hierarchical field is used for drilling down data. It means viewing your data at a more granular level.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What is a Tableau Data Server?",
        "answer": "Tableau server acts as a middle man between the data and Tableau uses. Tableau Data Server allows you to share and upload data extracts, preserve database connections, as well as reuse calculations and field metadata.\nThis means any changes you can make for the calculated field, data-set, aliases, definitions or parameters, can be saved and shared with others, that allows for a secure, centrally managed and standardized dataset as well as you can leverage your server's resources to run queries on extracts without having first to transfer them to your local machine.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is the Tableau Data Engine?",
        "answer": "Tableau Data Engine is a cool feature in Tableau. It?s an analytical database that designed to achieve instant query response, predictive performance, integrate seamlessly into existing data infrastructure, and it is not limited to load entire data sets into the memory.\n\nIf you are work with a large amount of data, it does take some time to create indexes, import, and sort data, but after that everything speeds up. Tableau Data Engine is not in-memory technology. The data is stored in disk after its import, and the RAM is hardly utilized.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) How to create a Calculated Field in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Click on the drop-down option to the right of dimension on the data pane and go to the create options and select the calculated field to open the calculation editor.\nName the calculated field and create a formula.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The dual-axis is used to visualize two different measures in two different chart types. A date column and two measures are necessary to build a dual-axis chart.\nThe different scales are used in the graph that helps the user to understand both measures.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What is the difference between the Tree map and Heat map?",
        "answer": "Tree map Heat map\nA treemap also does the same thing as well as it can be used for illustrating hierarchical data and part of whole relationships. A heat map can compare categories with color and size\nIn the heat map, you can compare two different measures together.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is the difference between Data Joining and Data blending?",
        "answer": "Data joining Data blending\nData joining is used when you are combing the data from the same source. Data blending is required two completely defined data sources in a report.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What is TDE file?",
        "answer": "TDE is a Tableau desktop file which contains a .tde extension. It refers to the file to include data extracted from external sources like MS Access or CSV file, MS excel.\nThere are two aspects of TDE file that make them ideal for supporting analytics and data discovery.\nTDE is a columnar store.\nTDE uses all parts of the computer memory from RAM to the hard disk and puts each piece to work what is the best for its characteristics.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What is the Story in Tableau?",
        "answer": "A story is a sheet which contains a sequence of dashboards or worksheets that work together to deliver information.\n\nYou can create stories to show how the facts are connected, provide context, and demonstrate how decisions relate to outcomes or make a compelling case. Each sheet in a story is known as a story point.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is the difference between discrete and continuous data in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Discrete Continuous\nDiscrete data is the value that is counted as distinct or separate. Continuous data is used to measure continuous data.\nOnly It can take individual values within a range. It can take any values within a finite and infinite range.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) How many numbers of rows Tableau can utilize at one time?",
        "answer": "Tableau is not restricted by the number of rows in the table. Tableau is used to access petabytes of data because it only retrieves the rows and columns.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) Can Tableau be installed on macOS?",
        "answer": "Yes, Tableau Desktop can be installed on Mac as well as window operating system.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) Tableau software is suitable for strategic acquisition or not?",
        "answer": "Yes, Tableau software is suitable for strategic acquisition because it gives data insight to the extent that other tools can't.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) Can we place an excel file in a shared location in Tableau?",
        "answer": "Yes, we can place an excel file in a shared location, but for better performance, we should use extract.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) Suppose license expires today, will users be able to view dashboard or worksheet which published on the server?",
        "answer": "If Tableau Desktop license expires today, then you cannot access the dashboard or worksheet because the username on the server will have to unroll unlicensed.\nBut others can access because the site admin can change the ownership to another person, so the extracts do not fail.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What are the different Tableau files?",
        "answer": "Bookmarks: It contains only single worksheet and its easy way to share your work.\nWorkbooks: Workbook can hold one or more dashboards and worksheets.\nPackaged workbooks: It contains the workbook along with any supporting local file data and background images.\nData extraction files: Data extraction files are a local copy of a data source or a subset.\nData connection files: Data connection file is a small XML file that contain various connection information.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is the difference between the published data source and an embedded data source?",
        "answer": "Published data source Embedded data source\nIt contains connection information which is independent of any workbook, and multiple workbooks can use it. It contains connection information, and it is associated with a workbook.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "tableau"
    }
]